Kashif Qureshi

Address: Clausthal, Germany Telephone: +49 176 46608761

Email: <u>kashif.qureshic10@gmail.com</u>

Date of Birth: 20.05.1985



Profile

I have 11+ years of professional experience on Microsoft .NET Technologies such as ASP.Net, C#.Net, ADO.Net and XML Web Services. I have experience in design, development and testing on enterprise applications developed in C#, ASP.NET, XML, SQL SERVER and oracle. I am looking for a job where I can fully use my skills to perform the given task and duties and to be a productive and flexible employee for the organization.

Professional Experience

10/2015 - 10/2021

Senior Software Engineer/Team Lead at Safenah Alrwad in Al-Ahsa, Saudi Arabia

07/2012 - 09/2015

Computer Programmer at Al-Hokail(SofDigital Systems) in Al-Ahsa, Saudi Arabia and Karachi, Pakistan

08/2011 - 06/2012

Senior Software Engineer at SofDigital Systems in Karachi, Pakistan

10/2008 - 07/2011

Analyst Programmer at Sidat Hyder Morshad Associates in Karachi, Pakistan

- Managing multiple production and development environment.
- Troubleshooting problems reported from developers and End-Users.
- Hands-on experience in administering various DBMS and system administration.
- Daily system administration and monitor backup schedules.
- Experience with Visual Studio Enterprise Edition 2010/2013/2015/2017.
- Knowledge and experience with Multi-Tier applications environments.
- Work with clients to understand new requirements and develop the technical specifications.
- Document system configuration and application enhancement if required.
- Provide technical and functional level guidance to other IT staff members.
- Managing day-to-day database and application issues to ensure system stability and output.
- Report team performance and project progress to Project Manager.
- Develop .Net applications and manage development team.
- Design and implement applications, development and deployment strategies.
- Conduct technical tests and interviews during hiring and selection of technical resources.
- Participate in code reviews for coding standards.
- Source control management with Team Foundation Server and Visual SVN.
- Work with trainees and trained them regarding the technology and worked with them on enterprise applications.

Projects

School Management System (Wagar)

Employee Self Service (HCM)

Human Capital Management

Saudi Irrigation Organization official website (https://www.sio.gov.sa/)

NoCancer Hospital Official website

Human Resource Management System

Makro HHT Solution

Project Time Keeper

Recruitment Portal

Email Sync Solution (Windows Service)

Database Sync Solution (Windows Service)

Education

2004 - 2007

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science from the University of Sindh

2021

Diploma in Strategic Management and Leadership

Certifications

Oracle Certified Professional
Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist
Scrum Fundamentals Certified

Languages

Urdu – Mother tongue English – C1

German – (Started Learning A1)

Knowledge and Skills

- Languages & Tools: .Net Framework 2.0, 3.5, 4.0+ (ASP.NET, MVC, NHibernate, C#, VB.Net, ADO.Net, Visual Basic 6.0, SQL, PL/SQL, Javascript, JQuery, XML, HTML), SqlGate, PLSQL Developer, Flutter, Dart.
- RDBMS: SQL Server 2000 to 2016, Oracle 9i, 10g and 12c and MySql.
- Software Packages: Visual Studio.Net 2005 to 2019, VS Code, Atom, Oracle Forms and Reports Builder, Crystal Report.
- Configuration Management: Dynamic Source Anywhere, Tortoise SVN and Visual Studio Team System